Dr David John Robinson

Seismologist Government Advisor Author Volunteer 5 O'reilly Street Macgregor ACT 2615

Home: (02) 6278 3829 Mobile: 0408 676 304

E-mail: david.robinson@anu.edu.au

Personal Statement:

Trained as a seismologist and with over a decade in the public sector, I have an interest in the communication of science to the general public, a skill recognised by: the Australian National University through the award of the Robert Hill Memorial Prize for scientific communication in 2007; and the Federal Government of Australia with the award of Distinguished Geoscience Australia Lecturer in 2005. Furthermore, I have received formal media training and have represented the government in all forms of media including television, radio (interview/talk-back), print and the Internet (news/forums). I have presented science to diverse audiences around the world including scientists, economists, government councilors, emergency managers and secondary students.

Publications:

My publications span a variety of forums including ARC A* rated international journals, professional magazines, official government reports and educational materials. I have negotiated and created high-level terms of agreement with significant international organisations and from 2003—08 I held the position of Associate Editor for the bi-monthly magazine Preview. I am currently working on a memoir of my family's struggle with Leukaemia, family deceit, life threating complications and ongoing uncertainty. The memoir provides an accessible overview of Leukaemia, its impact on the body and the mind and the manner in which it consumes those involved. Selected publications include:

- Robinson, D., Sambridge, M. and Snieder, R. (2011) A probabilistic approach for estimating the separation between a pair of earthquakes directly from their coda waves, *Journal of Geophysical Research*, 116, B04309.
- Robinson, D. (2010) Studies on earthquake location and source determination using coda waves, Ph.D. Thesis, The Australian National University, pp. 263.
- Barnhoorn, A., Cox, S., Robinson, D., Senden, T. (2010) Stress- and fluid-driven failure during fracture array growth: Implications for coupled deformation and fluid flow in the crust, *Geology*, 38(9): 779-782.
- Robinson, D., Snieder, R. and Sambridge, M. (2007) Using coda wave interferometry for estimating the variation in source mechanism between double couple events, *Journal of Geophysical Research*, 112, B12302.
- Robinson, D., Dhu, T. and Schneider, J. (2006). Practical probabilistic seismic risk analysis: A demonstration of capability. *Seismological Research Letters*, 77(4): 453-459.
- Robinson, D., Dhu, T. and Schneider, J. (2006). SUA: A computer program to compute regolith site-response and estimate uncertainty for probabilistic seismic hazard analyses. *Computers and Geosciences*, 32: 109-123.
- Robinson, D., Fulford, G., Dhu, T. (2005). EQRM: Geoscience Australia's Earthquake Risk Model: Technical Manual: Version 3.0. *GA Record 2005/01*, Geoscience Australia, Canberra, pp. 148.
- Dhu, T., Robinson, D., Sinadinovski, C., Jones, T., Corby, N., Jones, A., Schneider, J. (2002). Earthquake Hazard. In Dhu, T. and Jones, T. (ed.) Earthquake risk in Newcastle and Lake Macquarie, GA Record: 2002/15, Geoscience Australia, Canberra, 43-76.

Employment History:

2001—: Australian Federal Government, Geoscience Australia (GA).

Executive Level II, Earthquake Activity Leader, Risk Analysis Methods Section.

2010—: Visiting Fellow at the Research School of Earth Sciences, ANU

Research collaboration and co-supervision of higher degree students

2000: Flinders University of South Australia (FUSA).

Lecturer of the third year course 'Numerical Modelling in the Earth Sciences'.

1998—2000: FUSA.

Tutor for Introductory Mathematics, Intermediate Mathematics, Elements of Data Analysis and Mathematics for the Physical Sciences.

1998—1999: Aboriginal Tutorial Assistance Scheme

Mathematics tutor for Aboriginal students.

Formal Education:

2005—2010: Ph.D. in seismology at The Australian National University (ANU)

2001—2002: Graduate Certificate in Management at Charles Sturt University.

1999—2000: *First Class Honours* in Geophysics at Flinders University of South Australia (FU). University Medal winner.

1996—98: *Bachelor of Science* at FU - double major in Geophysics and Mathematics. Grade point average of 6.73 (out of 7).

1991—95: Schooling at Urrbrae Agricultural High School. Head prefect in 1995.

Notable Awards:

2007: Robert Hill Memorial Prize for scientific communication from ANU

2005: Distinguished Lecturer from GA

2001: University Medal from FUSA

2000: Max Clarke Prize in Science and Engineering from FUSA

Other:

1997—: Member Australian Society of Exploration Geophysicists (ASEG).

Served as Secretary, Vice President and President of the ACT Branch.

2006—: Member Seismological Society of America

2007—: Member American Geophysical Union

2012—: Member ACT Writers Centre

2012—: Volunteer at The Canberra Hospital

Advice and Assistance to newly diagnosed haematology patients

2003—2008: Associate Editor (Book Reviews) for Preview

Preview is the bi-monthly magazine of the ASEG.

1991—95: Member Fleurieu Peninsula Elite Swimming Squad

1994—97: Member Christies Beach Life Saving Club

Bronze Medallion Holder.

1993—2001: Involvement in Scout Association.

Member Port Noarlunga Sea Scouts (1985-1996). Queen Scout award (the highest award in scouting). Rock-Climbing Instructor (1993-2001).

Bronze and Silver Duke Of Edinburgh Award Holder.